Evan Sagge

Web Applications Developer Washington DC Metro Area +1.813.505.7366
http://evansagge@gmail.com/

I am a software developer with a focus on web applications development, with years of experience in various languages such as Ruby, Java, PHP and C/C++. I specialize in writing web applications, using mostly Ruby on Rails and Rack-based frameworks. I also write code in Javascript/Coffeescript and designing clean and simple HTML5/CSS3-compliant web UIs.

I am heavily influenced with agile development practices, mostly from Scrum, REST-ful web development, test-driven development, and later on behavior-driven development, ensuring that the desired software behavior are properly identified from a practical standpoint and at the same time focusing on delivering simple, efficient, and usable software.

In my free time, I enjoy playing soccer, hiking, running, biking, and traveling to new places.

Specializations

Ruby, Ruby on Rails, MongoDB, Javascript, Coffeescript, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3

Professional Experience

Systems Analyst at Gannett (http://gannett.com) - 2012 - Present

- Implemented Salesforce CRM backend requirements using Apex
- Developed Visualforce pages for Salesforce CRM
- Worked on Salesforce CRM integration projects using Ruby on Rails

Associate, Software Development at **iLab Solutions** (http://ilabsolutions.com) - 2011 – 2012

- Developed and maintained new and existing products and features for in-house web applications using Ruby on Rails and Javascript/Coffeescript
- Ported existing applications from using Prototype to jQuery

Consultant Software Developer at **Deal Grocer** (http://dealgrocer.com)- 2011 - 2012

 Developed additional features for main web application using Cuba (a Rack-based web framework) and Ohm (Redis-based ORM)

Technical Lead at Infinite.ly (http://infinite.ly) - 2010 - 2012

- Developed Ruby on Rails 3 web applications using MongoDB and background processes using Resque and Redis
- Implemented search and indexing capabilities using ElasticSearch
- Designed interfaces to connect with external web-based APIs such as Facebook Graph, Twitter, Google Data, and Flickr APIs to obtain social media data
- Managed remote server infrastructure on Linux instances using Nginx, Uni-corn, Bluepill, Monit and Newrelic

Software Engineer at Exist Global (http://exist.com) - 2008 - 2010

- Implemented and maintained web and mobile applications for various cli-ents, most of which are developed using Ruby on Rails technologies.
- Developed new features and enhanced existing functionalities for the TotSpot social networking web site using Facebook's OpenStream API and Twitter's OAuth API
- Developed a web-based photo-management application using Ruby on Rails 2.3.x and Facebook REST API
- Developed iPhone application to render photos as cartoonized images

Web Developer at **Syndeo Media** (http://syndeomedia.com) - 2007 - 2008

 Implemented new features and enhanced existing functionalities for client-based projects using Ruby on Rails Software Developer at **Solegy** - 2006 - 2007

 Developed and maintained new and existing software solutions using a mix of C++, Java (J2SE and J2EE) and Ruby coding languages

Software Design Engineer at **Blue Chip Designs** (http://bcdph.com) - 2005 - 2006

 Developed software solutions (drivers, firmware, desktop applications) for thermal printer devices, point-of-sales systems using C/C++ and OLE, Ac-tiveX, COM, MFC frameworks

Freelance Work

Training Payback (http://trainingpayback.com) - 2007 to 2008

 Developed new features and enhance existing functionalities using Ruby on Rails and PostgreSQL

Babyland (http://babyland.com.ph) - 2006

 Designed and developed the original website using CakePHP and MySQL

Schema Konsult (http://schemakonsult.com) - 2007

· Designed and developed the website using PHP and MySQL

Open Source Projects

Mongoid-RSpec (https://github.com/evansagge/mongoid-rspec)

- · RSpec plugin to provide matchers for the Mongoid ORM
- primary developer

Flickr-OAuth (https://github.com/evansagge/flickr_oauth)

- simple Ruby library for connecting to the Flickr API
- primary developer

Numeric Array (https://github.com/evansagge/numeric array)

- Ruby library extending Array objects to provide methods for mathematical and statistical calculations
- primary developer

CakePHP (http://cakephp.org)

- PHP-based web development framework, similar to Ruby on Rails for Ruby
- contributor from 2005-2007

Skills & Expertise

Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Sinatra, MongoDB, MySQL, PostgreSQL, ElasticSearch, Redis, HAML, Slim, Javascript, Coffeescript, Prototype, jQuery, CSS, SASS, Compass, Nginx, Passenger, Unicorn, Monit, Bluepill, Rack, Cuba, Salesforce CRM, Apex, Visualforce Pages

Education

- Ateneo de Manila University, Philippines B.S. Computer Engineering, 2000 - 2005
- Ateneo de Manila University, Philippines B.S. Physics, 2000 2004

References

Available upon request